

## Rafat Anwar Munshi

## Full Stack Developer

🖣 Mumbai, India 💹 munshi.rafat07@gmail.com 📞 7500602103 🏲 Indian

## **Profile**

Web Applications Developer with 5+ years of relevant experience developing Full Stack applications in the Technology, E-commerce and Education Industry. For me, technology is a tool leveraged to deliver on Business requirements and User Experience. I find satisfaction in writing clean, tested and quality code. I also take pride in my excellent communication skills.

## **Skills**

**BackEnd** 

Spring Boot, Hibernate, JUnit, Node.js (basic)

**FrontEnd** 

React.js (basic), JavaScript ES6

DevOps (basic)

Google Cloud Platform, GitLab CI/CD, Terraform

Database

MySQL, MongoDB

Python, Git, REST APIs, Docker

Knowledge of

Systems Design, Design Patterns

## **Professional Experience**

## 07/2012 -11/2014

## IT Engineer, Cisco Systems

**Business Applications Developer** 

Cisco Developer Network- www.developer.cisco.com ☐ (~1 year)

Role: Individual Contributor (Team size-8)

- Improved user experience and developed enhancements for the large-scale application by working closely with the team in the US.
- Built a Java API to upload videos to Cisco's video sharing platform as a reusable component for 100s of Cisco Engineers.

Tech: Liferay, Spring portlet MVC, Quartz Scheduler

*Delivery Collaboration Portal*- www.dcp.cisco.com ☐ (~1 year)

Role: Individual Contributor (Team size-7)

- Actively contributed under the Agile process, following clean coding practice with a test-driven approach for the complex application.
- Mentored 2 junior Developers to quickly overcome gaps.

Tech: Java, Junit, Oracle DB, JQuery

## 01/2015 -06/2016

## Web Consultant, Maroof Consultancy

Swag of India. (~1.5 years)

Role: Core team member (Team size- 6)

- Involved in ecommerce website development and analytics for UAE and India based markets
- Worked collaboratively with marketing, operations, and customer connection to keep up the product growth which increased website traffic and sales by 30%

Tech: PHP WordPress- WooCommerce, MySQL, Google Analytics, MailChimp

# 09/2016 – **Full Stack Applications Developer & Instructor, AMU**04/2021 Technical Assistant (Computer) - (~2 years relevant as a F

Technical Assistant (Computer) - (~2 years relevant as a Full Stack Engineer)

Internal Quality Assurance Cell (IQAC) Role: Project Lead (Team size-4)

- Owned end-to-end deliverables individually of software applications from feature discussions, requirement gathering, release milestone planning to designing then coding, testing, debugging, documentation, deployment and maintenance.
- Suggested practical and scalable solutions which improved efficiency of processes of a 15 persons team by more than 80%.
- Became first point of contact for software adoption by the 2000+ users.
- Reduced requests to the Director, IQAC by 75% by becoming subject matter expert

Other responsibilities (~2 years)

• Boosted practical learning of 600+ students with improved Curriculum and Teaching for Programming and Web Technology projects

## 11/2020 – Software Engineer, Recursive Lambda

01/2021 DevOps Engineer (~2 months)

- Setup infrastructure on Google Cloud Platform using Infrastructure As Code (Terraform) to run a Docker Containerised Python Flask app.
- Built CI/CD pipeline on Gitlab to deploy on different environments.

## 07/2020 − Online Course Instructor, Skill Lync 🗹

present

Educator (~10 months)
 Developed Industry relevant Full Stack Technology Course content and supported students technically to be job ready for Front End Development, Data Structures and Algorithms using Java and Python, Advanced Databases, Back-End programming for Java Web Applications

## Volunteering

06/2021 – present

## CodeYourFuture, Technical Lead

London,

• Lead a group of trainees to create a minimum viable product of a real-world project using the MERN stack.

UK

• CodeYourFuture is a coding school for refugees & disadvantaged people based in London, UK

## **Projects**

#### **Inventory Management System**

Semi-automatic system that manages and stores information of the college inventory. Tech: React.js, Node.js, MongoDB (~6 months)

## **Students Information Portal**

Web System for registration and storage of students' personal, admissions and fees detail with live status tracking. Tech: Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySQL (~4 months)

#### **Students Feedback Portal**

Web System for the university to gain and analyse feedback from students and faculty for their subjects and departments. Tech: Spring MVC, MongoDB, Google Charts API (~6 months)

## **Grievance Redressal System**

Web system to track, notify and store time-bound grievances of various stakeholders of the university Tech: Bootstrap, MySQL, Java (~4 months)

## **Faculty Information Portal**

Centralised Web system to store details of faculty members, their subjects, classes and attendance. Tech: PHP, MySQL (~4 months)

## **Education**

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech), Veermata Jijabai Technological Institute (V.J.T.I) CGPA- 8.5/10 Mumbai, India

2012